FROM ME TO YOU
DETERMINATION
What am I... supposed to do?
Sawako... Sawako!
Hello? Earth to Sawako!
Something wrong, sweetheart?
You're spilling rice all over the place.
You feeling all right?
Y-Yeah, I'm okay. I'm just
worried about exams, I guess.
Ah, of course. Those start tomorrow, huh?
Mhm. Thanks for the meal, mom.
Oh~ you're done already?
Yeah.
When I actually see Yano,
Yoshida, or even Kazehaya tomorrow...
I wonder... what I should do.
Oh, right. We're having exams today,
so our seats are in alphabetical order.
So who ended up in my usual seat?
It's Yano...
She's sitting in my seat like nothing.
Even though it's my fault she's being
gossiped about.
Come to think of it... Ever since I've
known them, Yano, Yoshida, and Kazehaya
have never tried to avoid me...
Nor have they been afraid of me.
They've always been... so kind.
Morning.
Sadako's seat? Wow,
what are the odds of that?
- I know, right?
- What about her?
Well, she typically takes the time to
greet everyone in class even though
they're freaked out by her, but today was
different. -She went straight to her seat
without even making eye
contact. -Why's that?
- There's a test today?
- I'm not sure...
But it means that's
not the Sadako we know.
To be honest... After moving away from my
assigned seat... it's almost like... it was
never there.
As if it never existed.
It feels like it was just
a dream. A distant one.
I didn't mean to cause trouble for any
of them. All I wanted to do was help.
Although... I still haven't been able to
clear up that misunderstanding with Yano
and Yoshida.
But what does it matter? Even if I find
whoever's spreading those rumors and
resolve everything... as long as I'm
around, I'm sure I'll only end up hurting
them again.
And they don't deserve that.
Things may straighten out eventually... But
Yano and Yoshida are hurting right now and
I have no idea how I'm supposed to
comfort either of them until then.
That's why... I think it's better to go
back to the way I was and distance myself.
It's for the best. I'm sure of it.
I wonder if Yoshida ended up using the
notes I gave her. Hopefully they helped,
even if just a little bit.
Guess what, Yano? I finally learned how to
tell a ghost story properly. I wanted you
to be the first one I told it to,
but... that probably won't happen.
And Kazehaya... I...
I... always felt so happy.
It was a feeling I've yearned for.
Something I've dreamed of... ...for so long...
I... don't know how I was able
to stand being alone before.
Now that I've gotten to experience how it
feels to be treated with kindness... How it
feels to reciprocate it...
It seems impossible to go
back to the way things were.
What was the point in being
alone? And why did I tolerate it?
I don't... remember...
Nothing's coming back to me.
Nothing.
Just like that first day of summer
break, Kazehaya was sitting here, waiting
- for me, in the same exact place.
- It doesn't make any sense.
If you don't hate me, then why avoid me?
"Don't... talk to me. Ever again."
Wait! I'm sorry, I take it back!
It's too hard to say something
like that when I don't really mean it!
Uh... what? -But I don't
wanna ruin your reputation!
Wha- Huh?!
Kuronuma!
Speak clearly so I can
understand what you're saying!
They say that I'll ruin your
reputation if you keep hanging out with
- me!
- What? Who's saying that?
- T-The rumors...
- Rumors?
Well, if they're about me, then how
come I don't get a say in any of this?
You don't get to make
decisions for me, Kuronuma!
I can make them myself!
I do... whatever I want to do.
If I wanna talk to you, I will.
And if I didn't want to, then
I wouldn't be here right now.
I don't care about rumors.
Why bother believing them? The
only one I choose to trust is you.
It's... what I've always yearned for.
To have a person like Yano,
Yoshida, or Kazehaya in my life.
It's something I've
dreamed of for so long...
Knowing what it's like
to care for someone.
And knowing how it feels to be cared for.
Feeling better?
Thanks, Kazehaya! I was super thirsty!
This should be enough.
Hm?
This definitely covers it.
Just a moment ago, I felt
so sad and discouraged.
How strange.
When Kazehaya smiles, my
clouded mind clears up instantly.
It's like... he's unravelling my heart.
Why bother believing them? The
only one I choose to trust is you.
When he said that...
It felt like him saying I could
stay by his side. It made me happy.
I see. So the rumors made it
awkward between you, Yano, and Yoshida.
Mhm.
- What if things were the other way around?
- Huh? Like if the rumor was that by
hanging out with you... Yano, Yoshida, and I
would ruin your reputation.
So we distanced ourselves from you.
I'd hate that!
I'd wanna stay together!
Bet Yano and Yoshida
would say the same thing.
It just depends on how
the other person feels.
We don't know what those two are
actually thinking... But if it's obvious
you're avoiding them,
they might get worried.
And if they're like me, I definitely did.
I am so so so so so sorry!
- So, enough!
- Huh?
No more, okay?
Ya got that? No distancing.
This is... different.
Instead of not letting me near them,
there's someone who won't let me avoid
them?
I... I guess I've been keeping my thoughts
to myself lately, haven't I? But I should
ask them... No...
They won't know if I don't just tell them.
It's important that I make everything
clear to Yano and Yoshida. I want them to
understand... exactly how I feel.
At least you know you can open up to them.
I'm... going to try
talking with Yano and Yoshida.
And I would like it very much if maybe
instead of just classmates... I hope we can
become f-friends... N-No! I will try my
absolute hardest and I will become their
friend!
I said it.
- Well...
- Huh?
Just do your best!
Right!
His kind words... and that smile...
they always push me to keep going.
Hang in there, Kuronuma.
You've got this. I know you do.
Good luck.
Kazehaya... Thank you. I'll make you proud.
I will do my best, I promise!
Why are you still here? Go home
already, you've got exams to study for.
That's why I was just
heading to the library, actually.
Really... You may not look it,
but you're pretty studious.
First of all, this
entire thing is your fault!
Huh?
If you hadn't popped
up at that exact moment-
What's with the irrational accusation
all of a sudden? If I hadn't "popped up"
when?
Thanks to you, we weren't able
to overhear Sadako's conversation.
What?
Just forget about it.
Hey. Don't play the blame game.
I don't really know what's going on in
your life, but I can tell you that nothing
will get resolved by blaming other folks.
Listen up, you're gonna be faced with a
lot of unfair stuff in the future...
It can be difficult sometimes, but you've
gotta learn how to figure things out on
your own. And that means even if I'm the
one who's causing the problems for ya!
Deal with it yourself, Yano!
Oh, and come to think of it, that paper
better have made its way over to Ryu's
- hands.
- That crap? I burned it to a crisp.
You did what?!
Don't play the blame game.
Give me a break.
I don't need that from him...
Isn't this the one Sadako was reading?
I was right.
YOTSUYA KAIDAN
TRUE GHOST STORIES
SAWAKO KURONUMA
This one too. But why is she
checking out Japanese horror stories?
She's an odd one.
At this point, why don't you think about
just using that image to your advantage?
It was a joke. Did she take it seriously?
She's so earnest.
Oh, you're sulking.
Do you need me to comfort you?
I am not sulking! What gave you that idea?
Ever since you were young, you'd sit out
here with the same look on your face after
getting kicked out of the
house for causing trouble...
Shut your mouth. So, what? You get back
from a jog? -Yeah, it's a secret training
- plan that Pin put together.
- Pin!
If that guy hadn't just
appeared out of nowhere...
I'm gonna guess the reason you're upset
isn't because people are saying you're a
delinquent. I don't give a crap
about some stupid rumor! Nah, I figured.
I'll be the first to admit I'm not that
smart. -So how am I s'posed to understand
all this?! Is Sadako really who she says
she is or does she have a dark-side
lurking within her?! -Can't
exactly say that I get it either.
Basically what happened was, someone...
told me the rumors came straight from
- Sadako.
- Okay and how'd she manage to
spread them around? Talking to herself?
If that was the case, people would be
gossiping about how she's a weirdo who
mumbles to herself all the time!
Well, it doesn't seem like
she has anyone to talk to.
Oh, my gosh! I didn't really think
about it before, but that's so true!
You idiot.
I just remembered she was talking to some
girl we didn't know. And one of the things
Sadako mentioned was that
we weren't her friends.
To be honest, she doesn't really seem to
like me and Yoshida at all. Because she's
kinda been avoiding us.
Jeez! What the hell did she mean by "I'm
sorry"?! I gave you the chance! Why didn't
you just say you liked us?!
Could be that she doesn't
feel that way about you two.
All right, wise guy... You sayin' she
hates us? Or that we were both bein' used
- by her?
- Who knows? Another
alternative is that she doesn't care.
But... There's also plenty of
other possibilities it could be.
What the... How do I
know which it is, then?
Beats the hell outta me. If
you're curious, why not ask her?
If she tells you she doesn't care, I've
got a shoulder you can come cry on. See
- ya.
- No thank you!
TO YOSHIDA-SAN
KEY POINTS
What'd he mean by "other possibilities"?
This is real easy to follow.
She did make these notes
especially for me, after all. Hm?
HANG IN THERE!
Sadako, your drawings suck so much!
She worked so hard... to make this for me...
Who else would do this?
Hey, Chizu. Are you able to come
meet me at the bridge right now?
Did your exam go well?
Uh... yeah. But mostly the parts
that Sadako's notes explained.
I see.
Ever since things got awkward between the
three of us, she hasn't even smiled once.
Just before that happened, it kinda
seemed like she was the happiest she'd
ever been.
I definitely saw a genuine smile when
we all studied for the exam together.
Yeah, that's right! I was
so surprised! We all were!
That Sadako...
Hm?
She was so used to being avoided by
everyone, that living that way seemed
completely normal to her. It actually
makes me depressed just thinking about it.
Because she's such a sweet girl.
That's why I chose not to
ignore her like the others did.
Yeah... That might explain it.
People ostracized her long enough for
her to become fully desensitized to it.
Eventually it spread to her own feelings.
It's weird but, I think I get why that
seemed like the only option. So when she
had such a genuine smile on her face
back then, it made me way happier than it
should have.
Wait, that was going through
your head at the time? Same for me.
Hey... Come on, don't
cry-it's embarrassing.
Kinda funny we had the same thought but
we're only learning that after the fact.
I can't believe we spent this whole time
thinking we knew Sadako pretty well, when
in reality we're totally frustrated
because it turns out that we knew nothing
about her at all. But to be fair, you
and I have a lot to learn about each other
too.
Yano, maybe we should talk about the
real reason we came out here in the first
place.
Sadako has no clue how we feel about
her right now or how anxious we are.
What'd she mean when she said "I'm sorry"?
And "they're not my friends..."
Or anything in that talk we had.
If we'd just asked directly, I
wonder... what would she have said to us?
She's nowhere near the type of person
I'd normally involve myself with. So, it's
really kind of funny that all I've
been doing is thinking about her.
It's frickin' annoying! Like, come on!
How much more is she gonna have us keep
worrying?
If anything, by having her on our minds
so often, it only proves just how attached
we've grown.
I once said that I couldn't answer, if
they asked about our friendship with her.
But I know now that's
definitely what it is.
After all, Sadako deserves it for
getting us to be this concerned about her.
You won't ever know someone's true
feelings unless you ask about them. Even
your own feelings will remain
unknown unless you convey them properly.
"I'd like to get to know you better, if
that's okay." I want how I feel to be
known.
And I don't have to worry if that's
alright for me to want. To have been able
to meet people who helped me get
to this point makes me... so happy.
When I run into Yano and Yoshida today,
I'll say, "C-Can we please talk for a
sec?" Wait, no... They probably study
during breaks, so maybe after school?
Ugh... but they'll be
studying for tomorrow too...
"I-I'm sorry to be a bother, but
can we p-please talk for a sec."
Hey... I-Is there a voice
coming from that stall?
Stop, you're scaring me!
I'm nervous, but... it's fine.
At least you know you
can open up to them.
I can tell them my feelings.
If anyone will listen,
it's Yano and Yoshida.
Oh man... I totally blew today's exams.
- Ugh. Yeah, tell me about it.
- No, no, no! I spent way too
long mentally preparing myself!
I've been meaning to
mention... Remember that Sadako rumor?
Yeah. The one about Yano
and Yoshida as her backup?
What?
- It turns out...
- It's... a misunderstanding!
Those two girls aren't my backup. Nor have
they ever been anything like that. Which
means... um... you're just
spreading around false information.
Yano and Yoshida are nice people
and I don't think they deserve this.
Did you hear her? She said
that they're "nice people."
Is this an excuse to talk to us?
- Ooh, she looks kinda mad.
- I, uh... This is how my face always
looks, but a-anyway... could we please-
Shut the hell up. We get it. This
is about Yano and Yoshida, yeah?
So, you understa-
Oh. Understand that they're a
slut and a delinquent~ course I do.
Mistakes to be fixed.
Lingering feelings.
Next time: "Friends"